<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Access in Youth Soccer | Tyler Richardett</title>
    <link>https://tylerrichardett.com/tag/access-in-youth-soccer/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://tylerrichardett.com/tag/access-in-youth-soccer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Access in Youth Soccer</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022 Tyler Richardett</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://tylerrichardett.com/media/logo_hu63450d64904b2806a1378e907e93ac54_121699_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>Access in Youth Soccer</title>
      <link>https://tylerrichardett.com/tag/access-in-youth-soccer/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Soccer Can&#39;t Afford to Continue Ignoring Children from Traditionally Underserved Communities</title>
      <link>https://tylerrichardett.com/blog/2018/10/11/u.s.-soccer-cant-afford-to-continue-ignoring-children-from-traditionally-underserved-communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tylerrichardett.com/blog/2018/10/11/u.s.-soccer-cant-afford-to-continue-ignoring-children-from-traditionally-underserved-communities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was originally published in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newamerica.org/weekly/america-cant-afford-ignore-vast-whiteness-soccer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;New America Weekly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One year ago Wednesday, a small, then-waterlogged village on the Trinidadian coastline served as the backdrop for American soccer’s terrible, horrible, no good, very bad day. With tired legs cemented firmly in a muddy pitch for 90 minutes, the U.S. men’s national soccer team tried, and failed, to qualify for this past summer’s FIFA World Cup. Now known in soccer circles as “Couva,” after the aforementioned village, the collapse, for the United States, marks the lowest point in the sport’s last two-plus decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just one day before the world’s biggest party kicked off in Russia, though, the United States was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.espn.com/soccer/fifa-world-cup/4/blog/post/3524721/how-2026-world-cup-bid-was-won-by-canada-mexico-and-the-usa&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;thrown&lt;/a&gt; a lifeline: the rights to host the tournament in 2026. (Well, 75 percent of it.) Participation in a World Cup, alone, offers several things: a chance for soccer to be relevant in an American landscape still dominated by other sports, the opportunity to welcome the next cohort of aspiring young stars into our expansive youth system, and an influx of sponsorship dollars to keep the whole operation running. &lt;em&gt;Hosting&lt;/em&gt; a World Cup offers the same—in multitudes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But experts have &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-soccer-worldcup-fifa-2026-usa/boon-expected-for-u-s-soccer-but-no-sea-change-as-world-cup-2026-co-hosts-idUSKBN1JA18F&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;warned&lt;/a&gt; not to expect a dramatic spike in youth participation. Two things stand in its way. First, soccer in the United States has a much stronger &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nbcnews.com/storyline/fifa-corruption-scandal/soccer-numbers-look-game-u-s-n365601&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;foothold&lt;/a&gt; this time around; growth rates will inevitably be smaller with a less-modest starting point. And second, and more important, youth soccer in the United States isn’t built to accommodate or sustain growth. That is, it’s exhausted the population of white children from well-off, suburban families who’ve long filled its ranks. Without &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; paving pathways for children from traditionally underserved populations, long &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2016/jun/01/us-soccer-diversity-problem-world-football&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;excluded&lt;/a&gt; from “the world’s great democratic game,” the U.S. soccer system will never enter the next stage of growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reaching peak success in the mid- to late 1970s, the old North American Soccer League (NASL) poured resources into &lt;a href=&#34;https://vdocuments.site/contextualizing-suburban-soccer-consumer-culture-lifestyle-differentiation.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;establishing&lt;/a&gt; a comprehensive network of grassroots youth soccer programs—the precursor to today’s network—before folding in 1984.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work constructed quite the runway to the 1994 World Cup: Between 1981 and 1991, participation in high school soccer increased by more than 83 percent. In the years immediately following the competition, soccer had secured its position as the second-most popular team sport for Americans under the age of 12 (7.7 million annual participants) by 1995, behind only basketball (9.7 million).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its followers, though, weren’t the ethnic minority groups, based predominantly in urban areas, that had quietly championed the sport in the United States in the preceding decades. Rather, they were white suburbians who, after effectively &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newamerica.org/weekly/edition-167/persistence-blame-game/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;distancing&lt;/a&gt; themselves geographically and economically from cities in the post-war era, sought further differentiation. Culturally, they embraced cosmopolitanism, and with the blueprint already having been laid by the NASL, soccer, as one sociologist &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.humankinetics.com/doi/10.1123/ssj.5.2.153&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;put it&lt;/a&gt;, and its “indeterminate signification made it available for ‘different uses.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put more bluntly, youth soccer was ripe for appropriation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, fast-forward to today, where that reality has played out. Data &lt;a href=&#34;https://tricha3.shinyapps.io/youth-soccer-virginia/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;confirms&lt;/a&gt; that, at least locally, access to competitive youth soccer diminishes as poverty rates rise. Majority-minority neighborhoods possess comparatively fewer opportunities than majority-white ones. And physical distance is the first thing standing in the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.forbes.com/sites/brucelee/2017/12/18/what-to-do-about-sports-participation-dropping-among-kids/2/#b6689215a06d&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;national survey&lt;/a&gt; of sport for development organizations, transportation is one of the largest barriers to access, with respondents “referring to long travel times, insufficient means of transportation, and safety in transport as significant concerns.” And for players who progress through the ranks and into more competitive environments, the demands of travel grow exponentially.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond geographic barriers, the “&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sandiegouniontribune.com/g00/sports/sd-sp-us-soccer-pay-to-play-u20s-20180814-story.html?i10c.encReferrer=&amp;amp;i10c.ua=1&amp;amp;i10c.dv=22&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;pay-to-play&lt;/a&gt;” structure sees families shell out thousands of dollars each year, for everything from uniforms to personal trainers. As a result, many more are priced out. (It’s worth noting that this issue is far from unique to soccer. Youth sports, by the latest estimates, &lt;a href=&#34;http://time.com/4913687/how-kids-sports-became-15-billion-industry/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;represent&lt;/a&gt; a $15 billion industry. Local governments are even trying to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/12/sports/youth-sports-costs.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;cash in&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the while, participation has &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wsj.com/articles/youth-participation-weakens-in-basketball-football-baseball-soccer-1391138849?tesla=y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;stagnated&lt;/a&gt;—or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/14/sports/world-cup/soccer-youth-decline.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;declined&lt;/a&gt;, depending on your &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.latimes.com/sports/soccer/la-sp-us-soccer-baxter-20180804-story.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;—over the last few years. Fortunately, reversing course isn’t impossible—and neither should it require too forceful an argument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above all, it’s a moral imperative. Integration of children from different backgrounds through sport &lt;a href=&#34;http://globalsportsdevelopment.org/2016/04/27/sports-as-a-tool-for-social-inclusion-and-social-change/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;promotes&lt;/a&gt; social inclusion. Participation in any sport from a young age is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncys.org/publications/the-benefits-of-youth-sports.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;correlated&lt;/a&gt; with improved physical health, psychological health, and academic performance. And, moving all the way to the top of the pyramid, there’s a case to be made for any national team to closely &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/parenting/wp/2016/09/09/soccer-in-the-u-s-still-looks-like-its-for-white-girls/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reflect&lt;/a&gt; the population it represents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some grassroots organizations have already started chipping away at the issues within their own communities. One solution, for example, sees a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.msysa.org/get_on_the_bus/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Maryland club&lt;/a&gt; meet children from low-income families after school, provide tutoring services and a healthy snack, and bus them straight to practice. Another has seen a &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/emilydona7/status/1030496931686957057&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Buffalo, N.Y., club&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aspeninstitute.org/blog-posts/urban-soccer-leadership-academy-opens-doors-latinos-texas/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;San Antonio, Texas, club&lt;/a&gt; carve out safe places to play within urban environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A non-profit in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/soccer-insider/wp/2017/10/29/in-d-c-a-small-step-toward-tackling-u-s-youth-soccers-accessibility-problem/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Washington, D.C.&lt;/a&gt;, and a club in &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@LA84Foundation/solving-youth-soccers-diversity-divide-4243f147baa1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Los Angeles, Calif.&lt;/a&gt;, each provide no-cost, competitive opportunities for children and teens of low-income families. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://theundefeated.com/features/u-s-soccer-foundations-got-a-brand-new-pitch/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;U.S. Soccer Foundation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.streetsoccerusa.org/mini-pitches/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Street Soccer USA&lt;/a&gt; introduce the sport to newcomers through unstructured “free play,” building small fields in inner-city neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the national level, a precedent for such change has already been set. Over the last decade or more, USA Swimming has made it a priority to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/parenting/wp/2016/09/09/soccer-in-the-u-s-still-looks-like-its-for-white-girls/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;address&lt;/a&gt; low participation among minority participants. Through the help of research, outreach programs, and mentorship programs for non-white coaches, African-American membership increased by 55 percent, and mixed-ethnicity membership by 77 percent, between 2004 and 2015. These efforts gained widespread attention in 2016, when Simone Manuel &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npr.org/sections/thetorch/2016/08/13/489614522/usa-swimming-wants-more-diversity-in-the-pool&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;became&lt;/a&gt; the first female African-American swimmer to win an individual Olympic gold medal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A leadership change at the helm of the whole system offers some reason for cautious optimism, too. Carlos Cordeiro, the newly-elected president of the U.S. Soccer Federation, campaigned on a platform that &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.archive.org/web/20180209033522/https://www.carlos4soccer.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;included&lt;/a&gt; making soccer “more accessible and affordable for youth, especially in our cities and underserved communities.” Cordeiro &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ussoccer.com/about/governance/board-of-directors/us-soccer-president-carlos-cordeiro/remarks-to-us-youth-soccer-annual-general-meeting-july-28-2018&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;echoed&lt;/a&gt; those sentiments as recently as July—already showing more interest in the matter than his predecessor of 12 years. (For reference, his Diversity Task Force webpage looked something &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20171120041044/https://www.ussoccer.com/about/governance/committees/diversity-task-force&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;like this&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soccer in the United States is at a crossroads. Layered over long-standing exclusionary practices, and reinforced by discriminatory federal housing, economic, and social policies, today’s commoditization of youth sports has left soccer even further beyond the reach of children from underserved communities, despite the fact that drumming up interest among and encouraging participation of young children is critical to the sport’s long-term success stateside. (The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ussoccer.com/about/about-us-soccer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;mission&lt;/a&gt; of the U.S. Soccer Federation, after all, is “to make soccer, in all its forms, a preeminent sport in the United States.”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At all levels, the system has ignored plenty of sound reasons to level the playing field. With the 2026 FIFA World Cup looming large, it’s now reached a point at which it needs to change, if for all the wrong reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Ways U.S. Soccer&#39;s Youth Task Force Can Make a Difference</title>
      <link>https://tylerrichardett.com/blog/2018/08/19/four-ways-u.s.-soccers-youth-task-force-can-make-a-difference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tylerrichardett.com/blog/2018/08/19/four-ways-u.s.-soccers-youth-task-force-can-make-a-difference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the 2026 FIFA World Cup bid in the rearview mirror, U.S. Soccer President Carlos Cordeiro now has his eyes set on an arguably taller task: opening the ranks of the youth game to those previously &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/football/blog/2016/jun/01/us-soccer-diversity-problem-world-football&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shut out&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.socceramerica.com/publications/article/78994/us-soccer-president-carlos-cordeiro-proposes-tas.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Speaking&lt;/a&gt; before U.S. Youth Soccer&amp;rsquo;s annual general meeting last month, the newly-elected president&amp;rsquo;s talking points on the matter matched the ones from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.carlos4soccer.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;campaign trail&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;ldquo;The landscape is too fragmented and fractured,&amp;rdquo; Cordeiro started. He also bemoaned an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2010/06/06/magazine/06Soccer-t.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;overemphasis on winning&lt;/a&gt; and the &amp;ldquo;high cost of &amp;lsquo;pay-to-play.&#39;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In search of solutions, Cordeiro&amp;rsquo;s pitch to the crowd was a modest one: a task force to assess &amp;ldquo;how we can do better.&amp;rdquo; If and when that task force comes to be, here are some ways it can start forging pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;create-a-centralized-system-for-information-sharing&#34;&gt;Create a centralized system for information-sharing.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t solve a problem you haven&amp;rsquo;t adequately defined. This may sound obvious, but know that, at this very moment, the sport&amp;rsquo;s leaders don&amp;rsquo;t even have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.latimes.com/sports/soccer/la-sp-us-soccer-baxter-20180804-story.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;definitive headcount&lt;/a&gt; of their active participants. By extension, they couldn&amp;rsquo;t possibly know &lt;em&gt;which&lt;/em&gt; players are there, nor which are missing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The task force&amp;rsquo;s first priority must be to answer those questions. And to answer those questions, they&amp;rsquo;ll need to work with member associations to develop a centralized and consistent method of collecting, storing, and analyzing this information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This could be a win-win for all parties. Cordeiro signaled toward strained relationships between the associations and the federation: &amp;ldquo;Some asked whether it still made sense to be a member of the Federation or whether the fees you pay are reasonable.&amp;rdquo; Developing a centralized system for information-sharing rights that ship, and it makes the day-to-day duties of administrators that much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Downstream, the benefits may continue to pile up. If sophisticated enough, such a system also has the potential to make scouting and talent identification more efficient. From the perspective of the athlete or parent, it could help them identify and carve out the most optimal pathway forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, however, it&amp;rsquo;s a step toward clearly defining the problem&amp;mdash;ensuring that all members of the task force start from the same place of understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;identify-the-areas-with-the-greatest-need&#34;&gt;Identify the areas with the greatest need.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. Youth Soccer CEO Christopher Moore last year &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uCuuYpyJlEQ?t=13m6s&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;admitted&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;ldquo;Knowing who your members are [is] the first step in being able to meet their needs.&amp;rdquo; And in fact, with respect to the previous point, Moore said his organization is taking the steps and building the technologies necessary to do so. One anxiety he shared, however, was that parents from underserved&amp;mdash;most often, Latinx&amp;mdash;communities are reluctant to share accurate demographic information given the current political climate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, data analysis is often steeped in logical assumptions and inferences. Identifying high-needs areas in the youth soccer landscape needn&amp;rsquo;t be an exception. A 2007 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/17267728&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; found that people who reside within a mile of a park are four times more likely to use it than those living farther away. And decades of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theatlantic.com/business/archive/2014/05/the-racist-housing-policy-that-made-your-neighborhood/371439/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;federal housing policy&lt;/a&gt; has resulted in the demographically homogeneous neighborhoods that exist today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, it&amp;rsquo;s not a massive jump to say: If we know where clubs and teams are playing, and if we know the racial and economic makeup of the populations in those areas, we know which kids are included, and which are excluded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent &lt;a href=&#34;https://tricha3.shinyapps.io/youth-soccer-virginia/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; of competitive youth soccer in Virginia did just that. And the results were in line with long-held assumptions: It&amp;rsquo;s a wealthy, suburban sport. Below, clubs in the Richmond and Norfolk areas are drawn out toward more well-off neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tylerrichardett.com/img/youth-soccer-va-maps.png&#34; alt=&#34;Maps of the Richmond and Norfolk areas of Virginia show competitive soccer clubs operating out of higher income, more suburban census tracts.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the right data made readily available, the federation, state associations, and non-profit groups could properly target resources so that, in Cordeiro&amp;rsquo;s own words, &amp;ldquo;kids from urban and rural areas and diverse communities can play, too.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;shrink-the-map&#34;&gt;Shrink the map.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The task force needs to tackle transportation as aggressively as any other issue. According to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.forbes.com/sites/brucelee/2017/12/18/what-to-do-about-sports-participation-dropping-among-kids/2/#b6689215a06d&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;national survey&lt;/a&gt; of sport for development organizations, transportation is one of the largest barriers to access, with respondents, &amp;ldquo;referring to long travel times, insufficient means of transportation, and safety in transport as significant concerns.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And for players who progress through the ranks and into more competitive environments, the demand of travel &lt;a href=&#34;https://tricha3.shinyapps.io/youth-soccer-virginia/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;grows exponentially&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One solution at the grassroots level sees a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.msysa.org/get_on_the_bus/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Maryland club&lt;/a&gt; meet children from low-income families after school, provide tutoring services and a healthy snack, and bus them straight to practice. Another solution has seen a &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/emilydona7/status/1030496931686957057&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Buffalo, N.Y. club&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aspeninstitute.org/blog-posts/urban-soccer-leadership-academy-opens-doors-latinos-texas/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;San Antonio, Texas club&lt;/a&gt; carve out safe places to play within urban environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spare time and money are not amenities afforded to parents working multiple part-time jobs. Often, financial aid can be made available, but as one club administrator wrote to me, that aid is turned down because, &amp;ldquo;they simply cannot get there.&amp;rdquo; For these families, the map needs to shrink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even Cordeiro has acknowledged, &amp;ldquo;Player development is not a single-lane road.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;acknowledge-the-limitations&#34;&gt;Acknowledge the limitations.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been beaten into a pulp: There&amp;rsquo;s no silver bullet for these issues. Beyond just that, many of these issues will be tackled for the first time. Cordeiro references an &amp;ldquo;eight-year runway to 2026,&amp;rdquo; but even that sounds ambitious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This will take time.&lt;/em&gt; And the task force should take the time necessary to get this right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the way, the task force needs to involve all the key players at the grassroots level. They understand the nuances specific to their locality, and they will ultimately be the ones carrying out recommendations. Without them, this proposed task force is useless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, it should go without saying, don&amp;rsquo;t lose sight of who matters here. To again borrow from Cordeiro&amp;rsquo;s remarks, &amp;ldquo;That love of the game, those hopes for the future&amp;mdash;that&amp;rsquo;s what youth soccer is all about.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
